At this year's
festival selection,
I'd like our workshop
to take part.
If we do, it might help us
return to our former--
[GLEN]
No.
Huh?
We will not participate.
But, sir...
I don't understand.
It's an opportunity
to rebuild the workshop.
[GLEN]
The last master refused.
But why?
It was us who originally
supplied the designs
for the Holy Beginnings Festival
until the previous monarch
changed the policies around it.
The selections began,
and we were never once chosen.
You see, the last master
of the Paige Workshop
was my father.
It was his choice.
The royal family
and the kingdom's religion
look down on us,
and this was his response
to that.
It's not my place to change it.
Why did they never choose
the Paige Workshop?
This conversation is over.
Then excuse me.
[door opens and closes]
[door opens]
[ANNE]
There has to be more to it.
There's some reason
why the Paige Workshop
has never been selected.
And right now,
our shop's missing something.
If you let us participate,
I think we can figure out
what it is.
I cannot change
my father's policies.
Not only that,
the legacy
that we have inherited
must not be disrespected.
But, sir,
what if the previous masters
were mistaken
in their decisions?
Mistaken?
Are you saying
they led us astray?
That they failed?
How dare you, Anne?
I believe
that everyone makes mistakes,
and it isn't something
to be ashamed of.
Do you realize
what you're saying?
I refuse to sit by and allow you
to insult our workshop.
If you claim that we're
perpetuating past mistakes,
then you're suggesting
that our traditions
are mistakes.
[ANNE]
I'm sorry if that insulted you,
but right now,
you're insulting me.
Pardon?
You've appointed me as the Head
of Artisans here at Paige
yet when you defended
your position just then,
you said "our workshop"
as though you believe
that I'm not a part of it.
But the truth is, I am.
Technically, you're not one
of our artisans, Anne.
You're wrong.
You invited me to join you.
You said that
you had high hopes for me,
with responsibility
as a silver sugar master.
So I'm going to fulfill
those responsibilities.
Whatever it takes,
I will rebuild this place.
Because that is my job.
[laughs]
Elliott?
It's nothing at all, I'm sorry.
Allow me
to escort her away now, sir.
If this goes any further,
I'm afraid she may cause you
to have an attack.
But I still have things to say.
Let's go, you can discuss it
another time.
[door closes]
[ELLIOTT]
My, my, what a spectacle!
To think you would defy
Mr. Glen himself.
I never thought
I would witness such a thing.
You know, if you disagree
with the way Mr. Glen
handles things,
I'm sure you could
say something yourself.
Assuming that I disagreed.
Huh?
The truth is, everyone
who's still at the workshop
either feels a deep sense
of gratitude for Mr. Glen
or at least a strong admiration
for him.
My mother used to be a cook here
at the main house
back in the day.
She raised me
and my older sister
all by herself.
But when I was seven years old,
she ended up sick
and wasn't able to work anymore.
The one who lent a helping hand
in our time of need
was old Mr. Glen.
I was too little to do much,
but he took me on
as an apprentice
so that I could earn some wages.
The others have a similar story.
All of us are here
because of Mr. Glen.
- [ANNE] Really?
- Yes, really.
Pardon, could you spare us
a moment of your time, please?
[ORLAND]
That should fix it.
Great, thanks.
We'll hurry
and get your meals ready.
I'm sorry to bother you
while you're working.
If you were sorry,
you wouldn't have done it.
But you're the one in charge
of maintaining it, aren't you?
[Orland sighs]
Honestly, you've been this way
since you were a child.
Oh, you've been here
for just as long?
Yes. Orland and I
have quite a storied history,
don't we?
My father was an artisan here
years ago.
After he passed,
Mr. Glen generously took me in,
that's why.
So, you know,
Orland never cuts his hair short
because he made a wish
a while back.
He hoped for Mr. Glen to be
cured of his illness someday.
Quiet.
[KING]
Are you two fighting in here?
Ugh, I'm really hungry.
Uh-oh, now the big
scary one's here, too.
[VALENTINE]
King used to be a ruffian.
He was so tough,
no one would cross him.
[NADIR] But Mr. Glen went
and hired him anyway.
Hm. That's ancient history.
I suppose
it was a little similar
to the way Nadir and I started
our employment at Paige as well.
If I'm remembering correctly,
Mr. Glen brought you onboard
because you weren't able
to pay your tuition, right?
Yes. He accepted me
despite how stubborn I was.
And even though
I'm from a foreign land,
he treated me
like one of his own.
Mr. Glen really is
the best, huh?
I think we should probably
go soon, Anne.
[ANNE]
Right.
Is something wrong?
Mr. Glen values tradition.
Everyone here looks up to him
and respects what he says.
It makes me wonder
whether problems can be hard
to see because you care.
If only everyone's feelings
could be united
toward the same goal.
Well, there are some things
that nobody
can do anything about,
but in those cases,
people tend to put their wishes
into sugar confections,
don't they?
Now, let's go eat some dinner.
[laughs]
[ANNE]
Everyone, gather around please.
What's that for?
I've missed the old feeling
of silver sugar in my hands.
Orland, you and King
should continue
with what you're working on.
Nadir and Valentine,
I'd like you to make something
with this to show me.
I want to see what you can do.
[ANNE]
Putting wishes into sugar.
[sighs]
- Amazing.
- It's impressive, right?
It's Valentine's favorite shape.
I don't get it,
but he says it has something
to do with math.
As for Nadir,
the more detail
he puts into a piece,
the more he likes it.
Customers have fallen in love
with his work for that reason,
so he gets requests often.
I see. That makes sense.
[door opens]
[ANNE]
Mr. Glen.
You should be lying down, sir.
I'll be all right.
The sweet scent of silver sugar.
Coming here
always lifts my spirits.
Orland, King, Valentine,
Nadir, and Anne.
I say this as the head
of the Paige workshop,
so listen.
We've always rejected
the Holy Beginnings Festival
selection process.
However, this year
we should participate.
Are you sure
that's all right, sir?
Only this once.
If we are not chosen,
then we will never
take part in it again.
What's more, I'll ask you
to leave this place
and that fairy
will remain here with me.
You're right, it's true
that I have chosen you
to be our Head of Artisans,
which means
you've taken on the
responsibilities that entails.
[ANNE]
Yes, sir.
As the Head of Artisans,
I can promise you
that I'll give it everything
I've got.
When I did that...
[ANNE]
Challe.
[CHALLE]
Have you finished all your work?
I have something
that I wanted to tell you.
Mr. Glen just came and told us
that we're participating
in the selection process
this year.
Although...
What is it?
If Paige isn't selected,
then I will be forced
to give up my job here,
and he's not going to give
your wing back to me.
Even so, I agreed to do it
because I think it's necessary
for the workshop.
That's why.
[CHALLE] If you deem it
necessary, then it's fine.
[ANNE]
Are you sure?
If we don't end up being chosen,
you'll be...
[CHALLE] You asked me
to trust you and wait,
so no matter what happens,
that's what I intend to do.
Oh, Challe.
Thank you. I'm glad.
And even if we don't succeed,
don't be afraid
because one way or another,
I'm going to retrieve
your wing for you.
I'm not afraid at all.
Good.
[Mithril laughing]
Sorry to startle you,
but it seems I've just
remembered an urgent matter.
I must take my leave.
The two of you should stay
and enjoy
this beautiful scenery.
In places like this,
some people hug,
hold hands, and even kiss,
if you can believe it.
What?
Please stop it, Mithril Lid Pod.
Anyhow,
have a good time, you two.
Especially you, Anne.
I don't need your advice.
Not that I would need it.
I have no idea
what he's talking about.
Just forget he was even here.
Wait, Mithril Lid Pod.
Please come back, I beg you.
What kind of confection
would be worthy of the festival?
Perhaps we should try a motif
that includes the Twelve
Patron Saints or the King.
Nah, I don't like big,
clunky things like that.
It'd be tacky.
Not just that, but statues
of the saints are boring.
If we did a flower,
then we could use more color.
Flowers in wintertime?
If the founding king
is the standard--
All right,
let's think some more.
- If we make something big--
- That's enough now!
[KING]
Huh?
You're all only suggesting ideas
that appeal to each of you
personally.
Only one of us is going to work
on the project, yeah?
Right, I should've realized.
Please pardon my rudeness.
You've got it all wrong, King.
Anne's going to make it.
Wait. Seriously?
Actually, I'm not.
Now historically,
the Paige Workshop
has assigned each commission
to a single sugar artisan,
but I've been thinking
of changing our procedure.
- Changing?
- That's right.
The five of us will come up
with an idea together,
and then we can all
bring it to life.
All five of us?
I highly doubt
that everyone's perspectives
will be aligned.
Moreover,
why do they need to align?
I'm glad you asked.
If we make a piece
we all approve of,
then it's sure to feature
everyone's best attributes.
Chances are,
if the five of us like it,
then the other people
are sure to like it as well.
[ORLAND]
If such a thing exists.
We'll never know
until we try to find it, right?
But where do we begin?
We can sit and chatter
all we want.
It doesn't mean
we'll agree on anything.
I mean, our ideas
and preferences
are all completely different.
I understand.
So then, what themes
have they selected in the past?
What sort of pieces won?
Maybe that information
would give us some hints.
That reminds me.
[ELLIOTT] These are the journals
of previous masters.
It's not the sort
of reading material
I'd ever go through. [laughs]
Why is that?
Trust me, you'll see.
Anyway,
I've got some things to do.
I'll be back tomorrow.
If you're still at it,
I'll try to help. Mm, yeah.
All right,
let's all start reading.
If we split it,
we'll be done in no time.
[KING]
I'm not so sure about that.
A secret language?
So, these journals are very old,
as are all the speech patterns
and they're hard to read.
I can't understand a word of it.
[NADIR] Neither can I.
Even if I died trying.
- I can read them.
- Hm?
I can manage as well.
So can I. Only us three?
The selection is less
than two weeks away.
Is there time?
All we can do is divide them up.
Three is better than none.
- Let's begin.
- Mm-hm.
Thank you.
- Sorry.
- So am I.
[ANNE]
It's all right.
Ooh, that must be challenging
to read.
It is, do you know
how to read it?
No, I don't.
Understanding that would require
a quality education
and a great deal of studying.
I know.
Perhaps young Miss Bridget
would have some success with it.
Speaking of which,
I haven't seen her around.
Apparently,
she won't leave her room at all.
[NADIR] Really? Fresh air
would do her good, though.
I agree.
- [crickets chirping]
- [knock on door]
[BRIDGET]
Who's there?
Challe?
Sorry, no, it's Anne.
Miss Bridget, there's something
that I was hoping
to get your help with, so I...
[BRIDGET]
My help?
Um, yes.
You see, we've been trying
to read the previous masters'
journals,
but they're hard to follow.
So, I thought
if we could have you help us,
then perhaps it would be...
[snickers]
If I agreed
to such a silly thing,
would Challe come
and pay me a visit?
Well, that decision
would be up to Challe.
I can't say one way or another.
Fine, then if Challe
doesn't come to see me,
I'm not helping you.
I understand.
Oh, just one more thing. Here.
What?
I was thinking of you,
and I made this.
It's for you.
[BRIDGET]
You made this for me?
I don't want it.
You're free to break it
and dispose of it.
You know well
that I'm not going to do that.
That's why I can't accept it.
I'll never accept it!
[ANNE]
Orland?
What were you doing in the hall?
What about you?
I don't know.
I wanted to give this
to Miss Bridget.
I thought if I did,
she might help us
with making sense
of the journals.
[ORLAND]
You are genuine to a fault.
She'd never accept that,
nor would she help you.
[ANNE] But you were bringing
her this one as well,
weren't you?
That's just a simple apology.
What for?
[sighs]
I'm the one
who stole Challe's wing
and put it on Mr. Glen's pillow.
[gasps]
Really? It was you who did that?
But what do you stand to gain?
I thought no one knew
about that hiding spot.
They simply don't remember.
Years back,
when we were young children,
we would play together.
It's been a long time,
but she showed me
where that hiding spot was
in the fireplace.
[ANNE]
I see.
[ORLAND] Bridget aspired
to become a sugar artisan,
so we were comrades.
She said that was why
we should share our secrets.
As a child,
she was cheerful and sweet...
but the person she is now
disgusts me.
I can barely look at her,
and she's been so cruel
to Challe,
so I stole the wing.
Do you think
Miss Bridget changed
because she was forbidden
to become a sugar artisan
like she wanted?
We're both girls, and I can.
You'd think the daughter
of a school master
would have that freedom.
Well, if the child of a master
becomes a sugar artisan,
they inherit the workshop.
Being in charge of a school
is already difficult,
it's even harder as a woman.
And you know our situation.
Mr. Glen didn't want
to leave his daughter
in such an impossible position.
He couldn't bear the thought.
[ANNE]
Once again,
everyone's feelings
are disconnected.
It's making things worse.
[MITHRIL]
There are some things
that nobody
can do anything about,
but in those cases,
people tend to put their wishes
into sugar confections,
don't they?
I understand.
All a person can do is wish.
[BRIDGET]
You made this for me?
Tell me something.
That sugar confection,
you made it
for Miss Bridget, right?
Your creations always have
a certain strength to them,
but when it's for Miss Bridget,
you can make lovely things
like this.
If it's in the service
of others.
According to what we've learned
from the journals,
the confections made
at the Paige Workshop
sometimes didn't align well
with the kingdom's religion,
which led to conflicts.
That's why they started doing it
by selection instead.
What's the bottom line?
Are you saying
that we should craft something
that caters to the kingdom's
religion this time?
Not at all.
It should be something
that we all want to make
to honor Mr. Glen.
[all gasp]
He wants to protect
the Paige Workshop.
That's why he agreed
to take part
in the selection for this year.
So, whatever we make,
we should make it for him.
Something that'll keep him
and the workshop going strong.
When Mr. Glen finally sees
our creation on display
at the Church
of Saint Lewiston Bell,
I want it to be something
that he can really be proud of.
Let's all give it our best.
But what should we make?
Now that I think of it,
every year,
Mr. Glen hopes for snow
on the night of the festival.
He says that snowfall can lead
us all into a brand-new world.
I've heard that snow
is one of his favorite motifs.
He'd love that.
So Mr. Glen favors snow.
I think we have our answer.
Let's create something
like that.
[HAL]
Help! Someone, come quickly!
Anyone, please! Hurry!
[all panting]
That sounded like Hal.
Oh. Mr. Collins!